Hey, he's still down.
(いの)ちょっと
アイツ 倒れたままじゃない！
(チョウジ)ナルト！
Naruto!
Naruto, are you all right?
(チョウジ)ナルト… 大丈夫？
(ナルト)うっ！
(いの)オッケー チョウジ そのまま支えて。
Okay, Choji keep him still like that.
(いの)ここじゃ 応急処置だけね。
Right now, I can only give
emergency first-aid.
それにしても まさか➡
But, who would've guessed...
あの 陽動の中に
オリジナルがいたとはね。
that the original was hidden
among the clones.
(チョウジ)ヘヘッ！
シカマルほどじゃないけど➡
You're not up to
Shikamaru's level...
ナルトも 頭いいほうなんだね。
but I guess you're pretty smart, Naruto.
シカマルと比べんなってばよ！
Don't compare me with Shikamaru...
But I'm impressed that
(ヤマト)しかし
よく３発も作ったね。 新術。
you were able to fire off
your new Jutsu three times.
(ヤマト)
修業でも ２発が限界だったのに。
Even during training,
two was the limit.
《カカシ : 失敗してから
次を あてるまでの機転の速さ…。
His quick thinking in making
his next move after failing only once...
His unshakable confidence...
強い自信…。
Naruto has truly become strong.
ナルトは本当に強くなってきた。
あの四代目でも
成し得なかった術を➡
Perfecting, to this level,
the Jutsu that even the Fourth Hokage
could not master...
ここまで ものにするとは…。
Looks like it's time to put
our trust in the next generation.
そろそろ 世代交代の時代だな
こりゃ…。
オレを超えやがったか…。
He's surpassed me...
感じてるか？ ナルトの目の先に
いつもいるお前が➡
Do you feel it?
You're the one Naruto always
envisions before him.
ナルトを
どんどん強くしていってるんだよ。
You are making him steadily stronger...
なあ サスケ…》
Isn't that so, Sasuke?
(ヤマト)先輩！ そろそろ。
(カカシ)あぁ。
Sir, we should get going...
Yeah...
うっ！
動けそう？
Can you move?
(ヤマト)よし みんな！
先に 木ノ葉に帰るか。
All right, everyone.
Let's go back to
the Hidden Leaf Village.
カカシ先生は？
(ヤマト)後始末。
Where's Kakashi Sensei?
Tying up loose ends...
(角都)お前らのような…
ガキどもに… オレが…。
How could I lose...
to young brats like you...?
Well, you're someone who's fought
against the First Hokage...
(カカシ)まあね。 初代火影と
戦ったことのある アンタだ。
オレたちが ガキに見えるだろうが➡
so we may seem like kids to you.
But to us,
you're just a washed-up old man.
オレたちから見たら
ただの ズレた老いぼれだ。
だから アンタは 今 ここで 死にかけ
はいつくばってる。
That's why you're near death
and groveling at our feet.
次から次へと 新しい世代が
追い抜いていくのさ。
One after another,
a new generation will succeed us.
(綱手)みんな ご苦労だった。
Good work, everyone.
The immediate danger has passed,
but the Akatsuki still remain...
当面の脅威は去ったが
暁は まだいる。
これからも気を抜くんじゃないよ。
Do not let down your guard.
Naruto, those wounds are...?
(綱手)ナルト その傷は？
Yeah, my badge of honor.
ああ 名誉の負傷だってばよ。
(サクラ)一応 応急処置は
済ませてありますが…。
We did some emergency treatment...
念のため 木ノ葉病院で
しっかり診てもらえ。
Just in case, get it checked thoroughly
at the Leaf Hospital.
いや… オレは 別に…。
Nah, I don't need...
Yes, you do!
別にじゃない！
Don't worry, Master.
大丈夫です 師匠。 私が
責任もって連れていきますから。
I'll take full responsibility
and take him there.
(サクラ)ねっ ナルト！
フゥ…。
- Got it, Naruto?
- Yes!
では これから お前たち２班には
しばしの休養を与える。
All right then, I order you
to take a few days off.
(綱手)おのおの
心身の疲れを癒やすように。
Rest your minds and
your bodies.
では 解散！
Dismissed!
気づいたか？
Did you notice?
Yes.
(シズネ)はい。
ナルト君の傷のことですね。
You mean about Naruto's wound?
I wonder what it could be?
何なんでしょう？ あれは…。
あんなのは見たことが…。
I've never seen anything like it...
What happened to the Akatsuki corpse
that Kakashi brought back?
カカシが持ち帰った暁の遺体は
どうなっている？
(シズネ)はい。 すでに
検死に回してありますが。
Well, it's already been sent
to the coroner.
では 担当に伝えろ。
優先して作業を急げ とな。
Then send a message to
whoever's in charge.
Make it a top priority
and put a rush on it.
(いの)やっと終わったね。
(チョウジ)…うん。
It's finally over...
Uh-huh.
(シカマル)悪い。
Sorry.
Huh?
えっ？
オレ ここでわかれるわ。
I'll part with you guys here.
But your house is this way...
でも 家って こっち…。
まあ ちょっとな。
I have something to do...
なによ もう…。
まあまあ。
What is it?
Now now.
Asuma Sarutobi
≪(シカマル)出歩いて いいんですか？
Is it okay to be up and about?
(紅)シカマル…。
Shikamaru!
(紅)将棋の相手が
いなくなったわね。
Your shogi partner is gone...
あなたは アスマの いちばんの
お気に入りだったから➡
You were Asuma's favorite,
寂しくなるでしょ？
so it will be lonely for you...
大切なことから
くだらないことまで➡
From precious things to silly things...
he taught me so much.
いろんなことを
教えてくれたんですよ。
将棋も そのひとつだった。
Shogi was one of them.
さみしくないっつったら
ウソになりますけど➡
I'd be lying if I said
I didn't feel lonely.
オレも もう いつまでも➡
But I'm no longer allowed
to act like a little kid ...
ガキのままじゃ いさせて
もらえない世代ですから。
I can't keep crying.
ピーピー泣いていられないっすよ。
オレ… めんどくせぇって
いつもダダこねてたから➡
I always complain about
what a bother things are,
and because of that,
I messed up a lot as a kid.
ガキの頃 そのせいで
失敗ばかりして…。
そのたびに
アスマに守られてばっかで…。
And each time,
Asuma was there to protect me...
Maybe that's why...
(シカマル)それでかな…。
although he was such
an evasive and odd teacher...
つかみどころのない
ヘンな先生だったけど➡
To me, he was a super cool grown-up.
オレにとっちゃ ムチャクチャ
かっこいい大人だった。
And that's why...
this time it's my turn.
だから 今度はオレの番すよ。
その子が生まれたら 今度は
オレが その子を守る師ですから。
When that child is born,
it'll be my turn to be
a protective teacher...
かっこいい大人にならねえと。
So I've gotta become
a cool grown-up too.
(紅)ありがとう。
Thank you...
さすが オヤジ。
アスマと違って強ええなぁ。
Boy, Pops.
Unlike Asuma, you're good...
(シカク)フン… 棒銀か。
...A Climbing Silver attack, eh?
What you'd call a necessary sacrifice
上手相手に玉を守るためには
犠牲もやむなしってヤツさ。
to protect the King
against a higher opponent.
(シカマル)そう 逃げたらほら
ここで桂馬だぜ。
If you escape there,
then a knight will come here.
So whichever the pawn runs to,
your bishop will be supported...
金のどっちが逃げても
角が成りこみか。
ったく その桂馬
いやらしい手だぜ。
Sheesh, that knight sure is
a nasty move there...
Well, if you're to compare
a Hidden Leaf Ninja to shogi pieces,
木ノ葉の忍を駒に
例えるなら オレは桂馬だからな。
I'm a knight.
何だそりゃ？
What does that mean?
Asuma said so.
アスマがそう言ってた。
ハッ… お前の性格をよく
わかってやがったな アスマのヤツも。
I guess Asuma knew
your personality very well.
Then, who would be the King?
なら 玉は誰にあたる？
((アスマ : なら 玉は誰だかわかるか？
Then do you know who the King is?
あっ？ 火影だろ？
Isn't it the Hokage?
オレもこの間まではそう思ってた。
Until recently, I thought so too...
But it wasn't...
けど そうじゃなかった。
んじゃあ 誰なんすか？
Then, who is it?
When the time comes,
you'll realize it too.
(お前も ときがくりゃわかるさ))
木ノ葉を担う これからの
子供たち… それが玉さ。
The children who will be taking over
the future Hidden Leaf Village...
They are the King.
フン…。
You know what it's all about.
よくわかってるじゃねえか
よっと 王手。
All right, checkmate.
(シカマル)なっ… あっ！
(シカク)テメエが玉を守るには➡
You don't have enough power
to protect the King yet.
まだまだ 力がたりねえな。
精進しろよ！
You better work harder!
(シカマル)クソッ！
Damn!
(サクラ)アンタって ホント
ムチャばっかりなんだから。
You're so reckless...!
Don't get so upset...
そんなに怒んなくたってさ…。
口ごたえしない！
And don't talk back!
Scrapes and bruises...
these injuries aren't too serious...
《擦過傷に打撲… たしかに
他の傷は たいしたことないけど➡
問題は この腕よ。
何か所も骨折してる》
The real problem is this arm.
It's broken in several places.
うっ…。
《術に 体が
もちこたえられていないんだわ》
His body isn't able to withstand
his Jutsu.
(綱手)なるほど…。 それが 角都を
担当した 検死班の見解か。
I see...
So that's the conclusion of
the coroner's team about Kakuzu?
Yes... Although they're not
completely finished yet...
(シズネ)はい。 すべての作業が
終わったわけではありませんが…。
(綱手)いずれにしても
担当上忍には➡
In any case, we must notify
the supervising Jonin about this.
伝えておかねばなるまいな。
(シズネ)いかがされますか？
What will you do?
Summon Kakashi and Yamato
to the coroner's room.
検死室に カカシとヤマトを呼べ。
I see...
(大蛇丸)そう…
飛段と角都が死んだの。
So Hidan and Kakuzu are dead.
Yes. It seems they were killed
by Naruto's team.
(カブト)えぇ。 やったのは
ナルト君たちのチームだそうですよ。
(大蛇丸)へぇ…。
Oh...?
生かしておけば
暁を もう一人くらい と➡
We thought they would take down
another Akatsuki
思っていましたが
うまく働いてくれたようですね。
if we let them live...
Seems like it went quite well.
悪くないわね。
Not bad at all.
I'm sure even the Akatsuki
would never have expected
暁の連中も さすがに
一度に２人ものメンバーを失うとは➡
to lose two of their members
at once.
想定してなかったんじゃ
ないかしら。
フフフフフ…。
とはいえ ヤツらは
二尾も手に入れている。
Still, they now have the Two-Tails.
このへんで もうひと押し
力を削ぐのがいいかもね。
Maybe we should give an extra push
to bring down their strengths.
例のあの子
どうなってるかしら？
How is that child?
はい。 近日中にも
最終実験を行う予定ですが➡
Yes.
I'm planning a final test
in a few days.
But judging from the data,
I'm certain there is no mistake.
データから推測するに
まず 間違いないかと。
I'm looking forward to it.
(大蛇丸)それは楽しみだわ。
《実行段階まで あと少し…。
Just a little more until
the final step.
But for that,
one more pawn is essential.
でも そのためには もう一つ…
どうしても必要な駒がある》
ねぇ カブト…。
Say, Kabuto. That woman...
あの女を ここに
連れてきてくれないかしら？
Would you bring her here?
…あの女を!?
That woman?
(綱手)検死作業は
まだ終わっていないが➡
The autopsy is not complete yet...
遺体を調べるうちに➡
Coroner's Office 1
But as we examined the corpse,
ナルトの新術について
わかったことがある。
we figured something out
about Naruto's new Jutsu.
こやつの受けたダメージは 打撃などの
通常攻撃によるものとは➡
The damage this fellow sustained
was caused by
something totally different
from the usual barrage of hits.
まったく別のものだ。
と いいますと？
What do you mean?
(綱手)体細胞に繋がる
経絡系の一つひとつが➡
Every Chakra Network connecting
his body cells has been severed.
すべて 断ち切られている。
経絡系が!?
あぁ そうだ。
His Chakra Network...?!
Yes. A condition like this
is usually unimaginable.
こんな状態は 本来ならありえん。
風遁 螺旋手裏剣
ここまでとは…。
Wind Style: Rasen-Shuriken...
is this powerful...?
これは 攻撃というよりは
毒の効果に近いな。
Rather than an offensive attack,
this works more like poison.
細胞レベルに ダメージを与える
極小サイズの攻撃…。
A microscopic attack that inflicts
damage at the cellular level...
おそらく 風のチャクラを
無数の小さな刀に 形態変化させ➡
I'm assuming that
the Wind Chakra
changed in Chakra Form
into infinite small blades...
体の細胞すべてを 攻撃した。
attacking all the cells
within his body.
なんて術だ…。
What a Jutsu...
Hmm... Poison...
う～ん 毒か…。
攻撃回数というより➡
Rather than the number of attacks,
攻撃濃度で表したほうが
的確ですかね。
it should be described as
a concentrated attack.
それで 術者である
ナルトのほうは？
And the user of the Jutsu, Naruto, is...
…問題は そっちだ。
やはり。
That's the problem.
I see...
カカシ その新術➡
Kakashi... This new Jutsu...
The Wind Style: Rasen-Shuriken.
風遁 螺旋手裏剣は
二度と ナルトに使わせるな。
Forbid Naruto from using it again.
そこまで…。
It's that serious...?!
ナルトの右手にも 同じ症状が
見てとれた。
The same condition afflicts
Naruto's right hand.
こやつほどではないがな。
Although it's not nearly
as bad as this one.
もし これ以上
新術を使い続ければ➡
If he continues using
this new Jutsu,
ナルトは… チャクラを練ることが
できなくなる！
Naruto will lose his ability
to mold Chakra.
これだけの術ですからね…
リスクも…。
With such a powerful Jutsu,
there's sure to be risks.
(綱手)
細胞が 経絡系からはがれたら➡
If the cells are disconnected
from the body's Chakra Network,
私の医療忍術でも 治せん。
even my medical skills
won't cure him.
ナルトにも 重々伝えておけ。
Be certain to emphasize that
to Naruto.
よりによって
あの女を呼ぶとはね。
Of all things, he wants
to summon that woman...
手荒い歓迎だな 紅蓮。
That was a rude welcome... Guren.
(紅蓮)クックックック…。
(紅蓮)なんだ カブトか。
Oh, it's just you, Kabuto.
I thought it was an intruder.
てっきり侵入者かと思ってさ。
わかってて
やったんじゃないのか？
You did that on purpose, didn't you?
まさか。
Of course not.
(紅蓮)それに
この程度で つぶれるようなヤツに➡
Besides, I wouldn't want
someone who'd die so easily
大蛇丸様の おそばにいられちゃ
困るんだよ。
to be standing beside
Lord Orochimaru!
Leaf Hospital
(サクラ)よし できた。
All right, done.
あとは しばらく安静にね。
サンキュ サクラちゃん。
Now you just have to take it easy.
Thanks, Sakura.
ねぇ ナルト… この新術は
ここぞってときだけにしなさい。
Say, Naruto. This new Jutsu.
Use it only
when absolutely necessary.
多用しちゃダメなんだからね。
Do not  use it too often!
大丈夫だってばよ。
サクラちゃんが治してくれれば…。
Don't worry.
If you can make it better-
I'm not talking about that!
そういうこと言ってんじゃないの。
医療忍術で なんでも すぐに
完治するわけじゃないんだから。
Medical Ninjutsu cannot heal
everything right away!
But this kind of makes me happy.
Huh?
I feel like you and I are
getting closer to Sasuke.
Geez...
Lady Tsunade...
でも… オレってば こういうの➡
we received word from
an Anbu Black Ops sent to another nation.
This is...!
Where is Kakashi right now?
なんか嬉しいんだ。
えっ？
He is probably with Naruto.
サクラちゃんと一緒に➡
サスケに近づいてる気がすっから…。
That's fine. Tell him to report immediately
once he's done with his business.
Could it be
a lead to Orochimaru?
もう！
Yes. It seems they were a step away
before being attacked.
ヘヘヘッ…。
We must select members for
a search
謎の組織… 暁について➡
今日は この方に
解説していただきましょう。
どうも ヤマトです。
さっそくですが
暁のメンバーって何人いるんですか？
かつては 10人いた
といわれています。
その後 イタチと対立した
大蛇丸が脱退。
さらに チヨバア様との戦いで➡
赤砂のサソリが死亡。
シカマルたちとの戦いで
角都 飛段が死亡➡
もしくは戦闘不能
となったため 現在６人。
そのうち 顔と名前が
わかっているのは 次の４人。
うちは イタチ。
干柿 鬼鮫。
デイダラ。
ゼツ。
残りの２名は 依然として不明。
現在も調査中です。
暁の最終目的をあばき
阻止するためにも➡
情報収集は 緊急の課題
といえるでしょう。
そうですね。 テレビの前のみなさん➡
この顔にピンときたら
木ノ葉まで よろしくね。